Hi, I'm Julian Lo

I design, develop, maintain and test apps

My GitHub My Facebook My Linkedin My Yelp Email Me c. 425-894-1133

Objective

I'm a UI developer — at Microsoft for 8 years — transitioning into mobile, full-stack, and open-sourced development. My strongest interest lies in building beautiful and delightful user experiences on mobile devices. My current focus has been on Android app development, and I am looking to get into iOS development as well.

Skill Set

Android/Android Studio, Java, Node.js/Express, Mongo, Amazon EC2 (1 year) C++, C++/CX, COM, Windows Runtime, Win32 (7 years) C#/.NET, XAML (3 years)

Employment History

Senior Software Engineer | Windows Spotlight (Windows 10) Microsoft | 2013 - 2015

<u>Windows Spotlight</u> is a feature introduced in Windows 10 that pushes fresh and beautiful images daily to users' lock screens on Windows devices. The feature also offers interactivity on the lock screen to provide users additional information on the image provided.

- Ideated, prototyped, and implemented UX for Windows Spotlight.
- Served as architect for UX code and mentored/led two junior developers also working on the feature.
- Tech: C++/CX, XAML, COM, Windows Runtime

Software Engineer II | Out Of Box Experience (Windows 8) Microsoft | 2010 - 2012

The "Out Of Box Experience" is the Windows component responsible for executing final per-machine setup/ provisioning tasks that must occur after the OS is installed but before the user starts using the machine. For Windows client installations, the component also displays UX for retrieving user input for things like account creation, EULA acceptance, and wifi connectivity.

- Worked on a complete rewrite of the feature to update the UX to modern Windows 8 UI.
- Tech: C++, COM, Windows Runtime

Software Engineer | HomeGroup UX (Windows 7) Microsoft | 2007-2010

HomeGroup was a feature introduced in Windows 7 allowing users on a single subnet (i.e. a home) to easily share files with each other.

 I was responsible for implementing wizard and control panel pages to allow users to configure their HomeGroup and network settings. (Tech: C++, COM, Win32)

Software Engineer Intern Electronic Arts Canada | 2006

I worked on the memory management system on NBA Live 07/08, ultimately replacing the existing system with an updated one borrowed from another product at EA. (Tech: C++)

J2SE/J2ME Developer Intern Tira Wireless | 2005

I was a "Jump Engineer", porting J2ME games built for Nokia phones onto other phones. This involved modifying production Java games and doing corresponding testing/verification on target devices. (Tech: Java)

Side Projects

Pics for reddit - Android app 2016

The app is a Reddit client, specifically for viewing image posts from Reddit.

- Key features include proper user token management, infinite scrolling lists, pleasant animations and transitions.
- Relevant links: Google Play Store, GitHub

Bathroom Maps - Android app, Node.js server 2015-2016

This app that helps locate public bathrooms, and allows users to suggest new bathrooms and write reviews for existing ones. (Tech: Android/Java, Node.js/Express, Mongo)

- Implemented a REST API built on Node.js to retrieve, review, and manage the list of bathrooms.
- Used Mongo DB and geospatial indexing for fast retrieval of bathrooms by geolocation.
- Built an Android app to view and review the bathrooms, caching data appropriately and allowing bathrooms to be filtered by category and rating.
- GitHub links: <u>Android</u>, <u>Server</u>. (Google Play Store release pending)

Picture Bible - Android app 2015

My first crack at an Android app. Picture Bible is a fun bible app that displays photos of architecture, food, nature, and animals behind each chapter. (Links: <u>Google Play Store</u>, <u>GitHub</u>)

Education

University of Waterloo - Bachelor of Mathematics Waterloo, ON | 2002-2007

- Majored in Computer Science, minored in Pure Mathematics
- Cumulative GPA of 85%

References

Available on request